Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.10.31 10:53:22
-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译:打酱油sky圆 校对:岁月倒影
对
Yeah.
我是詹姆斯・比尔斯
It's James Beels.
莱诺・卢瑟，他等我电话
Lionel Luthor. He's expecting my call.
我跟你说，我不管他是不是在开会 让他出来！
So how about this: I don't care if he's in a meeting, get him out of it!
告诉他我找到些东西！
Tell him I found something!
不，我不要等！把他给我叫来！
No, I won't hold! Get him!
你着什么急，伙计？
What's your hurry, pal?
嘿
Hey.
赶紧给我让开！
Move it, already!
别挡道！
Get out of my way!
嘿，车里那位！你没事吧？
Hey, in the truck! You all right?
嘿 嘿！来吧，我把你弄出来
Hey, hey! Come on. Gotta get you out of here.
冒烟了，我先把你放下
Smoke. Smoke. I'm gonna put you down.
没事了，振作点
All right, come on, now.
能听见我说话吗？你没事吧？
Can you hear me? Are you okay?
得把你弄走
We gotta get you out of here.
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
第十五集:尼哥底母
哈密尔顿博士
Dr. Hamilton.
客串主演:神川宏奈幸
I thought part of our arrangement was that you don't drop in on me.
我记得咱们的协议里有一条是 你不能来拜访我
我的实验室出了点状况
A situation's come up in my lab.
你是说你的仓库？
Don't you mean your barn?
有个员工偷走了我的一个实验对象
One of my experiments was stolen by one of your employees.
为什么卢瑟公司会有人知道你的工作内容？
Why would anyone at LuthorCorp know about your work?
- 他帮我安装新设备来着 - 他偷了什么？
-He was helping me install new equipment. -What'd he steal?
乔・莫顿 饰演 哈密尔顿博士
一盆花
A flower.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
You're kidding.
你开什么玩笑
It's called the Nicodemus. It's been extinct for a hundred years.
这花名叫尼哥底母 已经灭绝100多年了
我雇你是为了研究陨石对本地的影响
I hired you to study the effects of meteors on this town.
那才是你关注的焦点 你可是个地质学家
That is your focus. You're a geologist.
你何必浪费时间复活灭绝的花朵？
Why are you wasting time bringing flowers back from the dead?
我用陨石碎片辐射了休眠的种子
I irradiated the dormant seeds with meteor fragments.
我想知道的是它对人的影响 而不是对植物的影响
I want to know the effects on people, not plants.
这是第一步，科学就是这样的
It's a first step. That's what science is.
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
这是个过程，必经之路，你明白吗？
It's a process, a journey. You know what?
要么理解我，要么你就另请高明
Either you understand that, or you find someone else.
制片人:迈克尔・格林
制片人:道里斯・伊根
那人叫什么？
What's his name?
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
James Beels. I just found out he was in a car accident. He almost didn't make it...
制片人:鲍勃・哈格罗夫
詹姆斯・比尔斯，我听说他出车祸了 差点就没命了
不过另外一个开车的人救了他
...but another driver pulled him out.
- 别告诉我是克拉克・肯特 - 事实上是他的父亲强纳森
-Don't tell me it was Clark Kent. -Actually it was his father, Jonathan.
联合执行制片:肯・霍顿
妈妈？ 爸爸？
Mom? Dad?
剧本:迈克尔・格林
I just heard about the....
我刚听说…
故事:格雷格・沃克
I did not need to see that.
我不需要看到这场景
嘿，儿子，这是旧式对英雄的欢迎仪式 明白我的意思不？
Hey, son. Just getting the old hero's welcome, you know what I mean?
爸爸是怎么了？
What's going on with Dad?
我也不知道，他回家以后就一直奇奇怪怪的
I don't know. He's been acting strange ever since he got home.
导演:詹姆斯・马歇尔
嘿，克拉克，橄榄球赛直播开始了 和我一起看不？
Hey, Clark, football game on TV. You want to watch it with me?
你不是还有活要干吗？
Don't you have work to do?
那些活先推后
Chores can wait.
况且--哇!
Besides-- Whoa!
我有权休息，反正你可以帮我干活，不是吗？
I earned a rest. You can pick up the slack for me, can't you?
强纳森
Jonathan.
很高兴这场英雄事迹 没有冲昏你头脑
It's good to see this whole hero thing didn't go to your head.
- 但愿我没有唐突 - 嗨，莱克斯，进来吧
-Hope I'm not interrupting. -Hi, Lex. Come in.
有什么事，莱克斯？
What's up, Lex?
- 我是来找肯特先生的 - 你想干啥？
-I'm looking for Mr. Kent. -What do you want?
我听说你在车祸中救了我的一个雇员 我来看看你是否安好
I heard you pulled my employee out of a car, I wanted to see if you were okay.
才不是呢，你是想打探我是不是要告你
No, you didn't. You wanted to see if I was gonna sue you or not.
这样我就可以结束财务危机了，对吧？
That would put an end to all my financial difficulty, wouldn't it?
- 强纳森，够了 - 不，还不够，玛莎
-Jonathan, that's enough. -No, it's not enough, Martha.
你看，我不喜欢莱克斯・卢瑟…
You see, I don't like Lex Luthor...
我不喜欢莱诺・卢瑟 我也不喜欢你和我儿子做朋友
...I don't like Lionel Luthor, and I don't like your friendship with my son.
说实话，要是你们卢瑟家的人都死光光 我眼泪都不会掉一滴
In fact, if all of you Luthors were to dry up and die, I wouldn't shed a tear.
爸爸，够了
Dad, that's enough.
我去睡一会儿
I think I'll take a nap.
莱克斯…
Lex....
哇，喝啤酒，发牢骚 和你妈妈在橱柜上亲热？
Wow. Drinking beer, mouthing off and counter-macking with your mom?
祝贺你，克拉克，你老爸重返青春期了
Congratulations, Clark, your dad's regressed back to being a teenager.
他最近压力很大，我担心他是不是要崩溃了
He's been under a lot of stress, but I wonder if he's beginning to crack.
谁会一下午睡三个小时？
Who takes a three-hour nap in the afternoon?
不知道，但我还是暗爽他呛了莱克斯那通
I don't know, but I still like the part where he dissed Lex.
为什么？你和莱克斯有什么过节？
Why? What do you have against Lex?
我来数数，他把我家人踢出奶油玉米厂
Let's see. He screwed my family out of the creamed-corn factory.
那是12年前，不是他，是他父亲干的
Well, that was 12 years ago. And it was his father.
- 反正我不喜欢他 - 那你怎么从来没说过？
-I've never been crazy about him. -Why haven't you said something?
我本希望你能看清他的邪恶本性呢
I was hoping you'd see he was bad news.
你们心中最深处的欲望是什么？
What's your deepest desire?
如果没有任何约束，你会想做什么？
If nothing was holding you back, what would you do?
嗨，克罗伊，也很高兴见到你，咋了？
Hello, Chloe, nice to see you too. What's up?
关校长认为我应该紧紧把握学生脉搏
Principal Kwan thinks I need to get in touch with the pulse of the student body.
所以我决定做个调查 你俩得回应我的问卷
So I've decided to do a poll. Now, if you would both please do your statistical duty.
我会马上去和那个女孩亲热
I'd go over and make out with that girl right now.
我目前收到的答案都与性或暴力相关
You know, every answer I've gotten so far has been either sex- or violence-related.
这是人类的本性，克罗伊，再见
That's human nature, Chloe. Later.
嗨
Hi.
你知道皮特不喜欢莱克斯吗？
Did you know that Pete doesn't like Lex?
知道，他绝对嫉妒你和莱克斯的友谊
Yeah, he's totally jealous of your friendship with him.
他觉得他和你的关系不像以前那么亲密了
He feels you aren't as close as you used to be.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
（你最深的欲望是什么？）
What about you, Lana? Got one?
你呢，拉娜？什么想法？
我会爬上钱德勒农场的风车
I would climb the windmill out in Chandler's field.
真的？那就是你最深层次的欲望？
Really? That's your deepest desire.
有人告诉我从那里可以看到大都会的地平线
Somebody told me you could see the Metropolis skyline from there.
我一直没胆量自己去爬
I haven't got the guts to climb up and see for myself.
好吧
Okay.
- 我也可以编个别的答案 - 不用，挺好的，我喜欢
-I can always make something up. -No, it's good. It's good, I like it.
这就是无拘无束的拉娜内心
It's unleashing the inner Lana.
好吧
Okay.
行了，克拉克，该你了
Okay, Clark, you're up.
克拉克，注意啊，这调查分级属于PG-13
Clark. Remember, it's a PG-13 poll.
自从惠特尼的爸爸住院以来 拉娜周围就存在禁飞区了
Since Whitney's dad has been in the hospital, there's been a no-fly zone over Lana.
你该知道，还有别的女孩呢 不需要你穿越雷区就能得到的
You know, there are other girls out there that don't require crossing an emotional minefield.
但是又没有开关让我直接把对她的感情关掉
But I can't just turn off my feelings for her.
选择权在你手里
You know, the choice is yours.
要么坐在阁楼里玩你的望远镜，要么向前看
You can either sit in your loft and play with your telescope, or move on.
- 嗨 - 嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
咱俩一起去干草棚乐呵乐呵怎么样？
What do you say you and I go up into the hayloft and have us a little fun, huh?
现在不行，这边的活得有人干
Not now. Somebody's gotta do some work around here.
或许你该打电话给莱克斯道个歉
Maybe you would like to call Lex Luthor and apologize.
凭啥？我跟他说的都是实话
Why? All I did was tell him the truth.
我知道我说过应该释放你的感情 但是你现在做得太过火了
I know I said you should let your feelings out, but you're taking this too far.
你怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
没事
Nothing.
- 我觉得很自由 - 你看起来不怎么好
-I feel free. -Well, you don't look well.
你发烧了，要不躺一下吧 我回来给你做点汤
You're burning up. Why don't you go back to bed. I'll make you soup when I get back.
嘿
Hey.
- 我知道个治疗发烧的好办法 - 亲爱的，我真得走了
-I know a much better way to break a fever. -Sweetheart, I have to go, really.
肯特家，请留言
This is the Kents, leave a message.
强纳森，我是银行的吉姆・亚历山大
Jonathan, it's Jim Alexander over at the bank.
我直说吧，我们恐怕得拒绝你的贷款申请
I'm gonna be straight with you. I'm afraid we're going to have to turn down your loan.
喂，吉姆？给我听着
Hello, Jim? Yeah, listen to me.
我一直在给社区做贡献
I have done nothing but give back to this community...
而大家对我的回报仅仅是跟我过不去
...and all anyone has ever done for me is screw me over.
我这就去银行
So I'm gonna come down to that bank...
看你敢不敢当着我的面拒绝我的贷款
...and you are going to have to turn my loan down right to my face.
我倒要看看你是不是真的有种 还是被你老婆给藏起来了
That way I can see whether you have a pair or whether your wife keeps them in a drawer.
会不会开车，混蛋？
Where did you learn to drive, you jerk?
慢点！
Slow down!
爸爸，你干什么呢？
Dad, what are you doing?
我一直给社区做贡献，但是他们都跟我过不去
I've done nothing but give to this town, and they screw me over.
他们欺人太甚，我要反击了
They've pushed me too far, and I'm pushing back.
不能拿着把猎枪去啊
Not with a shotgun.
- 你别冲动，你没考虑清楚 - 我想得可清楚了，儿子
-You gotta slow down. You're not thinking. -I'm thinking just fine, son.
别挡道！
Now get out of my way!
克拉克
Clark.
爸爸
Dad.
他的症状是严重的过敏性休克
His symptoms indicate a severe anaphylactic shock.
- 但是检测不出任何已知抗原 - 那会是什么呢？
-But we can't detect any known antigens. -What is it then?
要是他昨天进来，我就会说这种症状前所未见
Truth is, if he'd come in just yesterday, I'd say I'd never seen anything like it.
但是我们今早收治了一个出车祸的人 叫詹姆斯・比尔斯
But we admitted a car-crash victim this morning, a James Beels?
他俩的症状一模一样
Showed identical symptoms.
就是爸爸救下的那人，他怎么样了？
That's the guy Dad saved. How's he doing?
不妙
Not good.
一小时前陷入昏迷了
He fell into a coma an hour ago.
咱们来干什么？
Okay, so, what are we doing out here?
肯特先生和比尔斯先生显示出相同的症状 这是他俩唯一在一起呆过的地方
Mr. Kent and Mr. Beels both have the same symptoms. This is the only place they've...
所以应该是这里的某物造成的
...been together, so I think what happened to Mr. Kent was caused by something here.
- 我们要找什么呢？ - 任何东西都有可能
-What are we looking for? -Anything.
哇，残骸从那边一直延伸到这沟里
Wow. The debris starts from way over there and ends over in that ditch.
这人开车真够冲的
That's some serious road rage.
我可能找到了什么
I think I found something.
发现什么了？
What you got?
对不起
Sorry.
没关系，咱们走吧，找不到什么线索
That's all right. Let's get out of here. This place is a dead end.
祝你健康
Gesundheit.
你没有对我完全说实话，哈密尔顿博士
Seems you haven't been completely honest with me, Dr. Hamilton.
我跟你说了，情况可控
I told you, it's under control.
两个人染上不明病症
Two men with an unexplained illness...
而没有人知道该怎么医治 这可不像是情况可控
...for which no one seems to know the cure isn't my idea of under control.
我对你擅自进行的植物学实验进行了一些了解
I did a little research of my own into your unauthorized botany experiment.
显然，1871年一种奇怪的传染病 席卷了摩尔利定居点
Apparently, in 1871 a strange contagion struck the Morley settlement...
一夜之间死了200人
...and 200 people died almost overnight.
一个传教士目睹了这一切并在日记中留下记录
A priest who witnessed the scene left a diary.
他的最后一条记录描述了人们举止异常
His last entries describe how the settlers began acting out of character.
他声称这是由当地的一种花导致的
He claimed a local flower was to blame.
"在上帝的绿色地球上，这种花是圣堂的盗贼
"On God's green earth, this flower was the thief in the temple.
沉默的妖魅，只需一个喷嚏 就将我们最深的欲望…
The silent temptress that, with a single sneeze, brought out the basest instincts...
挖掘出来，使人陷入暴力"
...in men and drove them to violence."
科学界仅仅将此视为民间传说
That's been relegated to folklore in scientific circles.
要是你不相信这种说法 那你就不介意我解开罩子闻一闻这朵花咯？
If you don't believe in this, you won't mind if I lift the lid and smell the flower?
你为什么要把它复活？
Why'd you bring it back?
这种花的毒素据说除了致命…
These flowers were believed to have toxins that, while deadly...
还有其它用途
...might have other applications.
我划提供资金不是为了让你养宠物
I'm not here to bankroll your pet projects.
我只对陨石感兴趣
I'm only interested in the meteors.
你想知道它们能做什么
You wanted to know what they could do.
我没打算因此把人送进医院
Putting people in the hospital wasn't the plan.
所有的发现都会有其后果
Every discovery has their consequences.
如果强纳森・肯特死了 你会失去的就不仅仅是你的职位了
If Jonathan Kent dies, you're gonna lose something more valuable than your tenure.
把你的花装好 我在大都会有一队科学家准备研究它
Pack up a flower. I've got a team of specialists in Metropolis to work on it.
- 这是我的研究 - 我才不在乎你的研究呢
-It's my research. -I don't give a damn about your research.
我只想找到治疗方法
I just want to find a cure.
哇
Wow.
为什么要穿成这样？
What's the occasion?
没什么，我只想咱们今天应该翘课
Nothing. I just thought we'd blow off class today.
我…
I....
我不能
I can't.
我勉强才跟上功课，我还得去商店
I'm barely keeping ahead, and I gotta go to the store...
然后去医院看我爸
...and then run by the hospital and see my dad.
你知道吗？我对你的借口已经厌倦了
You know what? I am tired of your excuses.
自从你爸病了，你就变得索然寡味
Ever since your dad got sick, you haven't been any fun at all.
对不起，拉娜，但这事马虎不得
I'm sorry, Lana, but it's kind of a big deal.
随便吧，我觉得我是出于愧疚 才被困在这种恋爱关系里的
Whatever. I feel like I'm locked in this relationship out of guilt.
拉娜，你怎么了？
Lana. What's wrong with you?
没怎么，我只是想坦白说出来
Nothing. I'm just not keeping it inside anymore.
如果你真这么想 或许咱们该重新审视咱俩的关系了
If that's how you feel, maybe we need to reconsider this relationship.
好吧
Okay, fine.
咱俩分手，惠特尼
It's over, Whitney.
- 嘿，吉米 - 哦，拉娜
-Hey, Jimmy. -Oh, Lana.
真棒
Nice.
不去上课吗，克拉克？
Not going to class, Clark?
我真没什么心情…去上课
I'm not really up...to it.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
没什么，你换了种打扮
Nothing. It's just a change.
你喜欢吗？
You like it?
我觉得更贴切的词是"唉呀妈呀"
I think the operative word is "gulp."
听着
Listen.
我知道事情不顺，但是你不能让这些拖垮你
I know things are rough, but you can't let them get you down.
这可不容易
It's kind of hard not to.
诀窍在于不去想它
The key is to keep your mind off it.
让你的朋友好好帮你
Let your friends be your friends.
让他们帮你分散注意
Let them distract you.
信任他们
Trust them.
我当然信任你，拉娜
I do trust you, Lana.
很好
Good.
那就跟我来
Then follow me.
咱们在这里干什么？
What are we doing in here?
这里好安静
It's quiet.
而且这么做完全…
It's also completely...
是被禁止的
...off-limits.
拉娜，我不觉得我想这么做
Lana, I don't think I'm really up for this.
你想得太多了，克拉克
You think too much, Clark.
我觉得你这会儿的表现不太像你自己
Right now I'm thinking you don't seem like yourself.
又或者…
Or maybe...
我比任何时候都更像我自己
...l'm more me than ever.
拉娜，这太疯狂了
Lana, this is crazy.
要的就是疯狂
That's the point.
要是生活不能让你疯狂，还活着干嘛？
If life doesn't make you crazy, then why bother living it?
我知道我想要这样
I know that's how I want it.
问题是
Question is:
你和我想要的一样吗？
Do you want what I want?
拉娜!
Lana!
你不想下来吗，克拉克？
Don't you want to come in, Clark?
我不太想
I don't think so.
我知道你想得到我，克拉克
I know you want me, Clark.
别再藏着掖着了，来吧
Just stop holding back. Come on.
你又不是钢铁之躯，或许你是的？
You're not made of steel. Or are you?
等等
Wait.
你还没等够吗？
Aren't you tired of waiting?
需要我帮你来个热身？
Need a little help warming up?
光彩照人的拉娜・郎在你面前就脱衣服了
She just stripped down in front of you. Lana Lang, in all her glory.
大部分时候是，但关校长不这么看
Most of her glory. Not that Kwan saw it.
至少你周六留校的时候 可以有好题材做白日梦了
Well, at least you'll have a nice picture to daydream about in Saturday detention.
很诡异，她说了所有我想听的话
She said everything I wanted to hear...
但是她自己好像没意识到她在做什么
...but it didn't seem like she knew what she was doing.
你觉得什么原因让拉娜变得轻佻了？
What do you think made Lana go soft-core?
先是我爸，接着是拉娜
First my dad, now Lana.
是啊，别忘了还有那个叫比尔斯的 记得你爸救下的那人不？
Yeah, and don't forget that Beels guy. Remember the one that your dad helped?
你们在事故现场一定遗漏了什么
You must have missed something at the accident site.
不，没有，我也去了那里，可我好好的
No, I didn't. Because I was there and I'm fine.
这真是说不通
It just doesn't make any sense.
等一下，看起来不只是我们在那里
Wait. Looks like we weren't the only ones out there.
那是谁？
Who's that?
我想这是哈密尔顿博士
I think it's Dr. Hamilton.
- 那个陨石狂人？ - 对
-The meteor freak? -Yeah.
他在树林里偷偷摸摸干嘛呢？
What's he doing skulking around in the woods?
我不知道，但是我觉得这不是巧合
I don't know, but I have a feeling it's not just a coincidence.
- 我去和他谈谈 - 我去找拉娜谈谈
-I'm gonna go talk to him. -I'm gonna go talk to Lana.
我觉得她和我爸爸有相同的遭遇
I think whatever happened to my father is about to happen to her.
我要的是比“进展”更有用的东西
I want something better than progress.
我刚才在医院，他们的情况恶化了
I was just at the hospital, they're getting worse.
拉娜，你去哪了？ 莫妮卡请病假了，我们缺人顶班
Where have you been? Monique called in sick, and we haven't got anyone to cover.
这关我什么事？
Why is this my problem?
因为妮尔去大都会了，你是助理经理
Because Nell's in Metropolis and you're the assistant manager.
我今天下午要放假，看来只有提前关门了
Well, I'm taking the afternoon off, so I guess we're closing early.
大伙听着，我们提前关门 咖啡不用付钱了，赶紧喝掉
Listen up. We're closing early, so coffee's on the house. Drink up.
我会回电的
I'll call back.
拉娜
Lana.
塔龙9点才关门
The Talon closes at 9.
今天例外
Not today.
你这态度可不好，拉娜
You're not impressing anyone with the attitude, Lana.
你这叛逆青年是在跟你老板打交道呢
You're talking to someone who set the bar for adolescent rebellion.
没错，我听说你来斯摩维尔前是个坏小子
That's right. I heard you were quite the bad boy before you joined us here in Smallville.
我并不以此为傲
It's nothing I'm proud of.
算了吧，你并不关心塔龙
Please. You don't really care about the Talon.
你投资它只是因为我请求你
You only invested because I asked you to.
你为什么要这么做？
Now, why would you go and do a thing like that?
卢瑟家向来以隐蔽的动机出名
The Luthors are famous for their ulterior motives.
所以告诉我，莱克斯，你真的是关心利润吗？
So tell me, Lex, was it really about profit?
我不确定你在干什么，但这不是你 拉娜，你是不是哪里不太对劲？
I'm not sure what this is, but it isn't you, Lana. Are you feeling okay?
事实上
Actually....
我有点紧张
I'm a little nervous.
我可能需要些指导，你知道…
I might need some guidance, you know...
来自某个比较有经验的人的指导
...from someone with a little more experience.
你觉得如何，老板？
What do you say, boss?
拉娜，你过去24小时去过哪里？
Lana, where have you been in the last 24 hours?
不关你的事
It's none of your business.
你有啥看不惯？
What's your problem?
这不是你
This isn't you.
为什么，因为我没有按吩咐办事？
Why, because I'm not doing exactly as I'm told?
因为我没有坐在角落里藏在书后面？
Because I'm not sitting in a corner hiding in a book?
我终于对生活不再恐惧，结果没人能接受
For once I'm not scared of life, and no one can handle it...
因为你们更喜欢那个缺乏安全感的小女孩
...because you all prefer the insecure little girl.
我受够她了，她只会谈论自己死去的双亲
Well, I'm sick of her and all her talk about her dead parents.
拉娜!
Lana!
哈密尔顿博士，你好 我是斯摩维尔火炬报的克罗伊・苏利文
Dr. Hamilton, hello. Chloe Sullivan, Smallville Torch.
咱们在网上讨论过陨石的
We spoke on the Internet about the meteors?
克罗伊
Chloe.
你能告诉我昨晚你在树林做什么吗？
Can you tell me what you were doing in the woods last night?
和我平常去树林所做的事一样
What I do there most nights.
搜寻陨石样本 我觉得用手电光更容易发现它们
Search for meteor samples. I find it easier to spot them with flashlights.
那么你没看见我和我的朋友了
So you didn't see me and my friend.
我听到了说话声，看到了手电的光亮 我知道孩子们喜欢聚会
I heard voices, I saw flashlights, I know that kids like to party...
你也知道，我不喜欢人多
...and as you know, I don't like company.
- 你不是在检查车祸现场？ - 什么车祸？
-You weren't looking at the accident scene? -What accident?
《尼哥底母日记》
我肯定是搞错了，抱歉打扰你了
I must be mistaken. Sorry to have bothered you.
你们昨晚在树林干嘛呢？
And what were you doing in the woods last night?
和朋友聚会
Partying with my friends.
拉娜，发生什么事了？ 莱克斯知道你开了他的车吗？
Lana, what's going on? Does Lex know you have his car?
这会应该知道了
He should by now.
你被什么东西影响了，我只是不知道是什么
Something happened to you, I just don't know what.
这叫自信，我终于不再压抑我的感情，我自由了
It's called self-confidence. For the first time, I'm not repressing my feelings. I'm free.
不，不是这样
No, you're not.
你还说呢，我在你面前跳入泳池 你都没敢冒一把险
You should talk. You had me in the pool, and you didn't take your chance.
我懂你看我的眼神 为什么你就是不肯告诉我你的感受？
I see the way you look at me. Why don't you tell me how you feel?
拉娜，你病了，我得送你去医院
Lana, you're sick. I need to get you to a hospital.
别转移话题，克拉克
Don't avoid the question, Clark.
你是不是爱上我了？
Are you in love with me?
拉娜…
Lana....
真是个懦夫，这么简单个问题都不敢回答
Such a coward. Can't even answer a simple question.
你想得到我？那就来呀
You want me? Come and get me.
拉娜，停下！
Lana, stop!
怎么了，克拉克？恐高？
What's the matter, Clark? Afraid of heights?
你干什么呢？快下来！
What are you doing? Come down!
拉娜！
Lana!
克拉克
Clark.
让开
Coming through.
发生什么事了？
What happened?
她和爸爸以及比尔斯的症状一样
She's got the same symptoms as Dad and Beels.
爸爸怎么样了？
How's Dad?
他陷入昏迷了，医生不知道他还能活多久
He slipped into a coma. The doctors don't know how long he'll last.
我已经让医生从大都会飞过来了 我会竭尽所能救治肯特先生
I've got doctors flying in from Metropolis. I'm going to do everything I can for Mr. Kent.
克拉克，我很抱歉
Clark, I'm sorry.
不是你的错，莱克斯
It's not your fault, Lex.
- 哈密尔顿博士的实验室有一本这样的书 - 尼哥底母日记
-Dr. Hamilton had a copy of this in his barn. -Nicodemus Diary.
这是斯摩维尔第一桩神秘事件的第一手记录
It's a first-hand account of Smallville's first mystery.
1871年，连邮局都没有的时候 整个定居点曾经疯狂
In 1871, the whole settlement went postal before they even had a post office.
原来斯摩维尔下陨石雨之前就遭过灾 我好欣慰啊
Nice to know Smallville was whacked before the meteors.
是的，在日记中记载了一种花
Yeah. In the diary, they talk about a flower.
定居者管它叫尼哥底母
The settlers called it Nicodemus.
他们说它能释放人压抑着的感情 使人愤怒，发烧，最终…
They said it liberated repressed feelings, sent them into rages, then fever and finally--
呃…
Well....
咱们在哪能找到这花？
Well, where can we find this flower?
问题就在这
You see, that's the glitch.
劫难过后，骑兵焚毁了这个定居点
After the massacre, the cavalry torched the settlement.
他们不希望灾难的根源传播开去
They didn't want whatever caused it to spread.
这花已经绝种100年了
The flower's been extinct for 100 years.
哈密尔顿怎么会和这个扯上关系？ 他是个地质学家
How is Hamilton involved in this? He's a geologist.
可他对陨石非常狂热
With a meteor fixation.
我们找到了他6年前写的论文
We tracked down this paper he wrote six years ago.
- 大都会大学校刊 - 我猜这就是最后一根稻草
-Metropolis University Press. -I think this is the last straw.
这里面，他提出假设 陨石可以用来辐射休眠的植物细胞
In it, he postulates that meteor rocks can be used to irradiate dormant plant cells.
所以你认为哈密尔顿把尼哥底母给复活了
So you think Hamilton brought back the Nicodemus.
- 现在他试图掩盖真相 - 咱们和他谈谈去
-And now he's trying to cover it up. -Let's go talk to him.
等等，还有呢 这本书不是哈密尔顿博士借出的，是莱克斯借的
Wait, there's more. Dr. Hamilton didn't check out The Nicodemus Diary. Lex did.
你认为他也牵涉其中？
You think he's involved?
我早跟你说过他不是好人
I told you all along he was bad news.
皮特，这么说为时尚早
Pete, we don't know anything yet.
好
Good.
我一会儿打回去 我刚和医生通过电话，他们已经分离出了病原
I'll call back. I just got off the phone with the doctors. They've isolated the problem.
和尼哥底母花有关系吗？
Does it have to do with the Nicodemus flower?
我知道你从图书馆借出了那本日记
I know you checked the diary out of the library.
- 是的，我借了，克拉克 - 为什么？
-Yes, I did, Clark. -Why?
因为我的公司地产建在那个定居点原址上
Because my property was built on the site of the original settlement.
我一直觉得那个故事很有趣 当我听说你爸的事…
I always thought it was an interesting story. When I heard about your dad...
- 我就追根溯源看看是否有帮助 - 问什么你没有告诉我？
-...I tracked it down to see if it could help. -Why didn't you tell me?
克拉克，那是个狂想家写的东西 我只是在寻找救命稻草
Clark, it's a crackpot story. I was grasping at straws.
- 你认识史蒂夫・哈密尔顿博士吗？ - 他是谁？
-Do you know Dr. Steven Hamilton? -Who's that?
别跟我撒谎！
Don't lie to me!
克拉克，冷静点
Clark, calm down.
我知道你担心你爸和拉娜
I know you're worried about your dad and Lana...
但是我仅仅是从图书馆借了书而已
...but I checked the book out of the library, that's it.
这事不是我的责任，但我在竭尽所能解决它
I'm not responsible for what happened, and I'm doing everything in my power to fix it.
这是实话，克拉克
That's the truth, Clark.
手电筒放低
Okay, keep your flashlight low.
现在你是擅闯民宅的高手了？
You're an expert on breaking and entering now?
当心！
Be careful!
皮特，怎么了？
Pete, what happened?
皮特？你没事吧？
Pete? You okay?
皮特？
Pete?
- 你在找我？ - 噢，不好
-You looking for me? -Oh, no.
你知不知道你美得没边儿？
Do you have any idea how beautiful you are?
行了，皮特，你被感染了，咱们得去医院
Okay, Pete, you've been infected. We've gotta get you to the hospital.
你老是这样，无视皮特 把我当成个可笑的家伙
That's right. Ignore Pete, he's just the funny guy.
你才不关心我的感受呢 因为你一心只想着克拉克
You don't sweat his feelings, because you've got eyes for Clark.
冷静点儿，皮特，我打给克拉克
Calm down, Pete. I'm going to call Clark.
他八成正跟他的新任好友 莱克斯・卢瑟打成一片呢
He's probably hanging out with his new best friend, Lex Luthor.
把你的车钥匙给我
Give me your keys.
为什么？你要去哪？
Why, where are you going?
我是认真的，克罗伊
I'm serious, Chloe.
把该死的钥匙给我！
Give me the damn keys!
他怎么样了？
How is he?
不妙
Not good.
克拉克，比尔斯先生半小时前死了
Clark, Mr. Beels died half an hour ago.
我使尽浑身解数仍然束手无策
With all my abilities, there's nothing I can do.
要是爸爸出了事，我们该怎么办？
What will we do if Dad--?
我不知道
I don't know.
我跟你说过我第一次见到他的情景吗？
Did I ever tell you about the first time I ever saw him?
没
No.
他去大都会大学上金融课 穿着牛仔工作服和法兰绒裤子…
He came to Metropolis U to take a finance course, and he was sitting by a fountain...
坐在喷泉旁边，吃着苹果
...all denim and flannel, eating an apple.
我向他借笔记
And I asked to borrow his notes.
他不知道我是那堂课的记录员 到现在仍然不知道
He didn't know that I was the note-taker for the class. He still doesn't.
你真狡猾，妈妈
You're sly, Mom.
他真可爱
He was so cute.
所以我向他借笔记，他就把笔记本递给了我
So I asked him for his notes, and he just handed over his notebook...
都没问我叫什么，于是我说：
...without even asking my name, and I said:
"你怎么知道我一定会还回来？"
"How can you be sure I'll bring it back?" And he said:
他回答说:"我愿意信任他人"
"I prefer to believe in people."
这很像爸爸的风格
It sounds like Dad.
我记得我看着他，十分尴尬
And I remember looking at him, completely embarrassed...
因为我产生了一个很傻的想法，我在想：
...because I was thinking the dumbest thing. I was thinking:
"老天啊，我希望我能嫁给他"
"God, I hope he marries me."
我仍然这么想
I still think that.
每天我心里都会隐隐浮现这句话 "老天啊，我希望我能嫁给他"
Every day there's a part of me that says, "God, I hope he marries me."
我很抱歉，肯特夫人 我能跟你说句话吗，克拉克？
I'm sorry, Mrs. Kent. Can I talk to you for a second, Clark?
去吧
Go.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
哈密尔顿博士在说谎 我在他的仓库发现了尼哥底母花
Dr. Hamilton was lying. I found the Nicodemus flower in the barn.
皮特也感染了，他变得好吓人
One got Pete, and he took a quick turn to scary.
- 他去哪了？ - 他拿着枪…
-Where'd he go? -He grabbed a gun...
说要去找莱克斯
...and he said he was going after Lex.
这花已经灭绝了100年了
This flower has existed for-- For hundreds of years.
美洲原住民或许已经发现了某种草药来解毒
Now, the Native Americans must have developed some sort of herbal antidote...
这是制药说明
...and these are the instructions.
- 你在哪发现的？ - 在博物馆收集的
-Where'd you find it? -Collecting dust in a museum.
- 这是独一无二的，他们还想拿回去 - 我会把这个交给我在大都会的小组
-It's a one of a kind, so they want it back. -I'll get it to my team in Metropolis.
谁都不许走
Nobody's going anywhere.
皮特
Pete.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我知道你是幕后黑手 你假意做克拉克的朋友，其实根本不是
I knew you were behind this. You pretended to be Clark's friend, but you're not.
现在他父亲就要被你害死了
And now his dad's gonna die. Because of you.
- 这是怎么回事？ - 别假装你不知道
-What's this about? -Do not pretend you don't know.
我去过你的仓库！
I went to your barn!
他被感染了
He's infected.
皮特，我们找到解药了 我们会把所有人都治好的
Pete, we have the cure. We're going to make everyone better.
你只是个骗子，克拉克没看出来 但是我看出来了，你要付出代价
You're nothing but a liar. Clark can't see it, but I can. And now you're gonna pay.
不！
No!
皮特，如果那本书烧毁了 你、拉娜和肯特先生都会死的
Pete, if that book is destroyed, you and Lana and Mr. Kent will all die.
你在说谎
You're lying.
皮特，我想帮助你
Pete, I want to help you.
你只想着你自己，根本不愿意帮助别人！
You don't want to help anybody but yourself!
你来到我们镇上 突然就成了克拉克最好的朋友！
You come to town and suddenly you're Clark's new best friend!
- 我本来以为他很会看人 - 莱克斯，那本书？
-I thought he was a good judge of character. -Lex, the book?
皮特，我要到那边把书取出来
Pete, I'm going to reach in there and grab that book.
如果你要开枪…
If you want to shoot me...
那就开吧
...go ahead.
没问题
No problem.
快走
Get out.
永别吧，莱克斯
Say goodbye, Lex.
皮特！别这样
Pete! Don't do it.
我们曾是最亲密的朋友
We used to be best friends.
他老爸害惨了我老爸 现在他又想搅乱咱俩的友谊
His dad screwed over my dad, and now he's trying to screw up things between us.
世界没有他会更美好
The world's a better place without him.
皮特，放下枪
Pete, put the gun down.
他是幕后黑手，我看见哈密尔顿来这儿了
He's behind all this. I saw Hamilton here.
他们一起策划的这件事！
They're working on this together!
- 这是真的吗？ - 克拉克，他产生鲁莽幻觉了
-Is that true? -Clark. He's delusional.
我不相信你 你说对了，皮特，他对每个人都不说实话
I don't believe you. You're right, Pete, he's been lying to everyone.
我知道我真正的朋友是谁
I know who my true friends are.
我就知道你会醒悟的
I knew you'd see the light.
克拉克，你要干什么？
Clark, what are you doing?
这事你逃不脱了，莱克斯
Can't talk your way out of this one, Lex.
我知道你的真面目了，友谊到此结束
I see you how you really are. The friendship is over.
打得好
Nice one.
我来干掉他
I'll finish him.
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
别担心，皮特，我们会送你去医院的
Don't worry, Pete, we'll get you to the hospital.
克拉克，搞什么啊？
Clark, what the hell?
对不起，莱克斯
I'm sorry, Lex.
所以刚才那是在演戏？
So that was an act?
我不知道还有什么别的办法 他会对你开枪的
I didn't know what else to do. He was gonna shoot you.
你差点连我都骗过了，我以为你来真的
You had me for a moment. I thought you were serious.
你在农场吃什么长大的？
What do they feed you on that farm?
哈密尔顿真来过？
Was Hamilton really here?
你觉得呢，克拉克？
What do you think, Clark?
早上好啊，小懒睡虫
Morning, sleepyhead.
爸爸，你好了
Dad, you're okay.
是的，克拉克 克拉克，我怎么会在这儿？
Yeah. Clark. Clark, what am I doing here?
强纳森！哦，亲爱的！
Jonathan! Oh, sweetheart!
- 玛莎 - 哦，亲爱的！
-Martha. -Oh, sweetheart!
昨晚大都会的医生找到了解药 是美洲原住民的疗法
The doctors in Metropolis found a cure last night. It was an old Native American remedy.
- 皮特和拉娜怎么样了？ - 他们已经下床了
-How are Pete and Lana? -They're already up.
- 爸爸，你还记得什么吗？ - 不记得
-Dad, do you remember anything? -No.
- 医生认为是发烧导致的 - 相信我，不记得最好
-The doctors think it's because of the fever. -Trust me, it's better that way.
- 那是怎么回事？ - 哦，亲爱的
-Come on, what are you talking about? -Oh, sweetheart.
哈密尔顿博士，你在吗？
Dr. Hamilton, hello?
- 你对我的实验室做了什么？ - 我毁了它
-What'd you do with my lab? -Destroyed it.
- 你怎么敢！ - 找到解药算你走运
-How dare you! -You're lucky you found a cure...
而且治好后没人记得发生的事
...and nobody infected can remember anything.
但还是会引人议论
But people are talking.
比尔斯是我父亲的员工 而且克罗伊・苏利文也有可能
Beels worked for my father, and then there's Chloe Sullivan.
我预感咱俩的合作关系到此为止了
I'm sensing this relationship is over.
不，博士，我认为你很有才华 你只是需要更严格的监督
No, doctor, I think you're very talented. You just need closer supervision.
我最近获得了大都会外的一处小型研究设施
I recently acquired a small research facility outside Metropolis.
卡德摩斯实验室？我会把你安置在那里
Cadmus Labs? I'm gonna hide you out there.
记住，莱克斯，是你打开了潘多拉的盒子
Remember, Lex, you're the one opening Pandora's box.
我只是钥匙，哈密尔顿博士
I'm just the key, Dr. Hamilton.
好了，睁开眼睛，拉娜
Okay, open your eyes, Lana.
那是大都会
There's Metropolis.
真美啊
It's beautiful.
真不敢相信咱们到这上面来了
I can't believe we're up here.
其实下去才比较困难
It's actually getting down which is gonna be the interesting part.
你能恢复回来真好，拉娜
It's good to have you back, Lana.
我花了一整天向塔龙员工 莱克斯和惠特尼道歉
I spent the entire day apologizing to the Talon staff and to Lex and to Whitney.
但就是不记得发生了什么
I just wish I could remember what happened.
听起来是我有点失控了
It sounds like I got a little out of control there.
你口无遮拦，做事随心所欲 有点像个拉娜女强人了
You spoke your mind, and you did what you wanted. Kind of an alpha Lana.
真不敢相信我那样穿衣服
I couldn't believe what I was wearing.
我还有点喜欢呢
I kind of liked it.
我没对你说什么或者做什么尴尬的事吧
I didn't say or do anything embarrassing to you that I should know about...
有吗?
...did I?
没有
No.
那就好
Good. Good.
那么，现在在世界之巅感觉如何啊？
So how does it feel to be on top of the world?
或者至少是在斯摩维尔小镇之巅？
Or at least Smallville?
我觉得很自由
I feel free.